他们不一样
They are not.
就一样
They are, too.
种种数据显示  你的假设完全不能成立
Your hypothesis is completely disconfirmed by all the data.
现在纯粹是你的智商在死鸭子嘴硬
You're just clinging to it out of intellectual stubbornness.
是你正表现出对谈话主题的
No, you're displaying a shocking ignorance
高度无知
of the subject matter.
木乃伊与僵尸是一模一样的东西
Mummies and zombies are the exact same thing.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
木乃伊全身裹着绷带呢
Mummies are wrapped in bandages.
那是人家的时尚风格
That's called a fashion choice.
好吧  是你自己自讨苦吃
All right, you brought this on yourself.
谢尔顿  说死丫的
Sheldon, get him.
如果你被僵尸咬了
If a zombie bites you,
你也会变为僵尸
you turn into a zombie.
但如果是木乃伊咬你
However, if a mummy bites you,
你只会变成有木乃伊咬痕的白痴
all you turn into is some schmo with a mummy bite.
所以你就像是个
So, like a zombie,
被人啃掉下半身的僵尸一样
that's been eaten from the waist down,
说的话完全"站不住脚"
you, sir, have no leg to stand on.
真乖  赏你个饼干
Good boy. Here's a cookie.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
大家伙在干嘛呢
Hey, fellas, what's going on?
又在辩木乃伊跟僵尸呢
Mummies and zombies again.
他们不一样好吗
Oh, they're not the same thing.
也赏你个饼干
You get a cookie, too.
谢谢
Thanks.
你们猜谁今早弄了台新车
Guess who picked up his new car this morning?
恭喜你啊
Congratulations.
-里面有新车味吗  -有的
- Does it have that new car smell? - Yep!
只要不让我妈上车就有
For as long as I can keep my mother out of it.
你们想看一下的话
If you want to check it out later,
就停在外面哦  294号位
it's parked right out front, space 294.
等等  294号位吗
I'm sorry-- 294?
-是的  -那是我的停车位
- Yeah. - That's my parking spot.
你怎么会有个停车位
Why do you have a parking spot?
你都没车  你连车都不开
You don't have a car. You don't even drive.
那无关紧要
It doesn't matter.
那停车位是我的
That's my spot.
可能是看你从不停车  就重分配给人了吧
Maybe they reassigned it because you never use it.
我也从不用我的乳头啊
Well, I'm not using my nipples, either.
他们也要帮我重分配吗
Maybe they should reassign those.
谢尔顿  哪天你买车了
Sheldon, someday, if you get a car,
他们肯定还会再给你个停车位的
I'm sure they'll give you another parking space.
我不要别的停车位
I don't want another parking space.
我要我那个停车位
I want my parking space.
那可是完美车位
It's perfect.
那车位是在角落
It's a corner spot,
车门被旁车门撞凹的机率少了一半
cutting the risk of door-dings in half.
而走到楼入口处也只需仅仅28步
It's a mere 28 steps from the building entrance.
旁边的树能在热天提供遮阴
The nearby tree provides shade on hot days
而且那树还是一只可爱小松鼠的家
and is also home to a delightful squirrel.
这很难得呢
Which is fortuitous
毕竟大多数的松鼠都是讨厌鬼
because most squirrels are real jerks.
故事虽好
Fun story.
但你就是没车啊
Meanwhile, you still don't have a car.
别想转移话题
Don't try to change the subject.
我们是在谈停车位
This is about a parking space.
跟有没有车毫无关系
It has nothing to do with cars.
你有听到你自己说的话了吗
Are you listening to yourself?
我当然都有听啊
I always listen to myself.
这是我人生中最美好的事之一呢
It's one of the great joys of my life.
快把你的车开离我的宝位
Now, get your car out of my spot.
不要
Nope.
你不仁
Very well.
那就别怪我不义了
You leave me no choice.
看个屁啊  你个白痴松鼠
What are you looking at, you stupid squirrel?
生活大爆炸 第六季  第九集
塞伯特校长  请听我的理由
President Siebert, listen to reason.
我知道我没有在使用那个停车位
Yeah, I understand I don't use the parking spot,
但这不是重点  我...
but that's not the point. I...
我知道你说过别打去你家
Yes, I'm aware you told me not to call you at home.
但这是因为你不应门啊
But you didn't answer the door!
我知道你在家
And I know you were there,
我当时从信件投递口看到你在里面了
because I saw you through the mail slot.
你这话够掉身份啊
Well, that's some salty language.
您别忘了您重点大学校长的身份啊
May I remind you that you're the president of a major university,
而不是个脏话俱乐部的主席
not the president of the Potty Mouth Club.
你又说
There it is again.
你也是用那张嘴亲你母亲的吗
Do you kiss your mother with that mouth?
好吧  请节哀顺变
Oh, well, I'm sorry for your loss.
晚安
Oh...! Good night, sir.
太扯了
Unbelievable.
他说我的停车位给沃罗威茨不为过
He says Wolowitz deserves my spot
因为他是学校的重要资产
because he's a high-profile asset to the university.
他也没说错啊
Well, he's not wrong.
霍华德好歹也上过国际太空站了
Howard did go to the International Space Station.
那都是五周前的事了
Yeah, that was five weeks ago.
他还想靠那件事占便宜多久啊
How much longer is he gonna milk that cow?
算了啦  谢尔顿
Sheldon, let it go.
也不是什么大事
It's not a big deal.
莱纳德  不反抗只会令他更予取予求
No, no, this is a slippery slope, Leonard.
先是占了我停车位
It starts with a parking space.
食髓知味了以后呢
Where does it end?
就像我爸说过的一样
It's like my dad always said,
"一开始只说不能酒后开车
"First they say you can't drink and drive.
才刚同意  就立刻再进一步说
Next thing you know, you can't let your 10-year-old
不许让10岁儿子开车  而自己去后座睡觉"
take the wheel while you sleep one off in the backseat."
你这故事只让我更心疼你妈
All that story does is make me feel bad for your mother.
莱纳德  你是我最好的朋友
Leonard, you're my best friend.
为什么你从不跟我同一阵线
Why don't you ever take my side?
因为我从没懂过你那阵线
Because I can never understand your side!
还我
Give it back.
很抱歉
I'm sorry,
您是指...
but could you be more specific?
我的钢铁侠头盔
My Iron Man helmet.
库萨帕里看见你拿了  还回来
Koothrappali saw you take it. Give it back.
哦  那个啊
Oh, that.
听我说  这东西我想要
Well, see, I wanted it,
你又不用  我就拿了
and you weren't using it.
我们现在生活规则好像是这样哦
Apparently, those are the rules we live by now.
报复
Payback--
还真是让人想骂脏话  不是吗
it truly is the B word, isn't it?
谢尔顿  那可是价值500美元的限量珍藏品
Sheldon, that is a $500 limited edition collectible,
快还给我
and I want it back.
我也想还给你  但很遗憾的是
I'd love to help you out, but unfortunately,
我在用呢
I'm using it.
好吧
Fine.
那我把你的学位证拿走
I'm taking your diploma.
尽管拿
Go ahead.
你这辈子唯一"拿到"博士学位的机会哦
That's the only doctorate you'll ever get.
里面闻起来怪怪的
It smells funny in here.
我们真以你为傲  艾米
We're so proud of you, Amy.
-你的初次比基尼蜜蜡脱毛呢  -对啊
- Your first bikini wax. - Yeah.
感觉如何
So, how you doing?
有点小敏感  但还好
A little sensitive, but not bad.
一般都需要这么长时间的吗
Does it always take that long?
不  他们一般不需要跑去多拿点蜜蜡
Uh, no, they usually don't have to go out and get more wax.
除完我感觉都轻了5磅
I feel like I'm five pounds lighter.
真的吗  你确定只有5磅吗
Really? Only five?
谁想来一杯
Hey, anybody want a drink?
-好的  -当然
- Okay. - Sure.
你昨晚是不是也得听他
So, did you spend last night hearing
抱怨那场白痴的停车位大战
about this silly parking space fight, too?
抱怨了好几小时
For hours.
幸好  因为谢尔顿戴着那个白痴面具
Fortunately, I couldn't understand most of it
他说的话我大部分都听不懂
'cause Sheldon was wearing that stupid robot mask.
霍华德气得要死
Howard was so angry
我不得不把过敏药混在他的冰淇淋里
I had to mash up Benadryl in his ice cream
Benadryl是儿童抗过敏药
一般小朋友吃了都会想睡觉
才能让他消停睡觉
to get him to fall asleep.
我猜这就是我们
I guess this is what we get
跟两个荷尔蒙爆棚的雄性霸主在一起的后果
for being with two testosterone-fueled alpha males.
一山不容二虎
At some point,
他们总有一天得角斗分生死
they're bound to lock horns.
我猜你说的"角"  是他们从动漫展
I'm assuming these are some kind of horns
买的什么号"角"之类吧
they bought at Comic-Con?
我很抱歉学校收回谢尔顿的车位
I'm really sorry they took Sheldon's spot away.
他不该因为霍华德
He shouldn't have to suffer
现在是个大咖  而蒙受苦难啊
just because Howard's such a big deal now.
是啊  谢尔顿应该大度点
I know, Sheldon should just let Howard
也让霍华德有一次受瞩目的短暂机会
have his little moment in the sun.
你这话什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
霍华德这辈子不会再上太空了
Well, Howard's never gonna go to space again,
但谢尔顿一辈子都会是个天才
but Sheldon will always be a genius.
有道理
You're right.
谢尔顿肯定有机会重获个好车位啊
And I'm sure Sheldon will get a fancy parking spot again,
假设他哪天真对科学做了有价值的贡献就行
if and when he makes a worthwhile contribution to science.
假设与哪天吗
If and when?
好了  或许我们该换个话题
Okay, maybe we should change the subject.
艾米  你"小妹妹"那里感觉如何
Amy, how are your lady parts?
还凉飕飕的吗
Still chilly down there?
打住
Hang on.
谢尔顿所有的理论
None of Sheldon's theories
都未获得最终证实
have ever been definitively proven.
而我的老公可是真正上过太空
My husband actually went to outer space.
那的确是一项令人赞叹的成就
That's an impressive accomplishment.
他现在成功鼓舞了百万美国人
He's now an inspiration to millions of Americans
就算你不特别  甚至不够格
who know you don't have to be special
也都可以登上外太空
or even qualified to go into space.
我还记得我第一次尝试比基尼脱毛
You know, I remember the first time I got a bikini wax.
我姐姐是用熔化的蜡笔和胶带帮我
My sister did it with melted Crayolas and duct tape.
那主意蠢透了...
It's a bad idea...
天啊  艾米
Gosh, Amy.
我感觉到了一丝敌意啊
I'm sensing a little hostility.
是不是因为  你们的性生活
Is it maybe because, like Sheldon's work,
跟谢尔顿的研究一样纯属"理论"啊
your sex life is also theoretical?
毒啊
Damn.
是啊  至少等我们开搞了后
Yeah, well, at least when we do make love,
谢尔顿脑子里不会想着他妈妈
Sheldon won't be thinking about his mother.
没错  我就是在明嘲暗讽
And yes, that is a cleverly veiled reference
霍华德他这辈子痴迷着想
to Howard's lifelong obsession
爬回他妈宽敞无比的子宫的心里
to crawl back into her spacious womb.
时至今日  我一看见蜡笔
Anyway, to this day, I still can't see
还是会吓得赶紧夹紧双腿
a box of crayons without crossing my legs.
我没必要听你冷嘲热讽
I don't have to take this.
老娘现在就回家跟我的老公做爱
I'm gonna go home and have sex with my husband right now.
可能还让他干我"停车位"呢
Maybe I'll let him do it to me in the parking spot.
虽然听起来很淫荡  但我不是那个意思
Which sounds dirty, but I didn't mean it that way!
好吧  另外一个问题
Okay, here's another one
如果僵尸咬了吸血鬼
If a zombie bites a vampire,
然后吸血鬼咬了人类
and the vampire bites a human,
那那个人类会变成吸血鬼  还是僵尸
does the human become a vampire or a zombie?
或是僵血鬼
Or a zompire?
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
饼干拿来
Cookie.
我没有
I don't have any.
我才不无偿帮你
Well, I'm not giving it away.
你好呀  谢尔顿
Hi, Sheldon.
他坐在我的专位上
He's in my spot.
莱纳德  让他别裸体坐在我的专位上
Leonard, make him stop being naked in my spot.
霍华德  你这是干嘛
Howard, what are you doing?
他又没在坐
He wasn't using it.
而我刚好需要一块冰凉的皮革
And I needed a nice cool piece of leather
来[摩]擦我的光屁屁
to wiggle my naked ass on.
快滚开
Get off there.
把我的钢铁侠头盔还给我
Give me back my Iron Man helmet.
把我的停车位还给我
Give me back my parking space.
你又不需要停车位
You don't need a parking space.
你连车都没有
You don't have a car.
你又不需要钢铁侠头盔
You don't need an Iron Man helmet.
你又不是钢铁侠
You're not Iron Man.
看来我们陷入僵局了
Well, we appear to have reached an impasse.
不过我得说  我原以为
And you know, I have to say, I thought
把你笔记本放我的大雕上  你会更生气呢
you'd be more upset that your laptop is sitting on my junk.
我刚还没发现  这招不赖啊
I didn't pick up on that. That's a nice touch.
霍华德·沃罗威茨
人家好激动
This is so exciting.
都感觉有点刺痛了
I'm feeling all tingly.
但也有可能是因为
Although that could just be
我才把比基尼部位除了毛哦
my newly defoliated bikini zone.
把好风
Keep a lookout.
这地方有一大堆校园保安
This place is swarming with campus security.
他们会骂死我们的
They will not hesitate to scold us.
死猪头
Freaking pigs.
谢尔顿·库珀
爽啊
Oh, yeah.
好的  现在
Okay, now,
把你的车开进来  我们就可以走人了
pull your car into the spot and let's get out of here.
等等  我得把车留在这里吗
Wait, I'm leaving my car here?
对  记得拉手刹
Yes, and be sure and put on the emergency brake.
这样要拖走你车都得废很大劲
Really makes these things tough to budge.
在我停车以前  你到后座来一下
Before I park, come in the backseat.
我给你看看我今天做的事
I want to show you something I had done today.
好啊  我都好奇起来了
All right, color me intrigued.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
你喷漆味吸高  嗨过头了吧
I think you're high on paint fumes.
老天  好多创口贴啊
And boy, that's a lot of Band-Aids.
你每一张结婚照里都有霍华德的妈妈
Okay, Howard's mother is in, like, every one of your wedding photos.
我能说什么呢  她可是"大"姑娘
What can I tell ya? She's a big girl.
不管看哪  她都赫然在目
Wherever you look, there she is.
再来点咖啡吗
More coffee?
不了  莱纳德要带我去听物理讲座
No, Leonard's taking me to a physics lecture,
咖啡会害让我睡不着
and coffee'll just keep me awake.
我去开门
Oh, I'll get it.
看来某人和伯纳黛特是一队的啊
Oh, looks like someone's on Team Bernadette.
霍华德在哪
Where's Howard?
他不在  怎么了
He's not here. What's wrong?
他让我的车被拖走了
He had my car towed.
花了我200美元才弄回来
It cost me $200 to get it back.
这么惨啊
Oh, no.
车本来在哪停着的呢
Where was it parked?
在谢尔顿的停车位
In Sheldon's spot.
不对啊  谢尔顿没有车位
That doesn't make sense. Sheldon doesn't have a spot.
是不是在霍华德的车位呀
Was it maybe in Howard's spot?
别装傻了  丫头
Don't play dumb with me, sister.
告诉你丈夫  他欠我200块
You tell your husband he owes me $200.
这也说不通啊
Well, that doesn't make sense, either.
怎么会
Why not?
因为车是我拖走的
Because I'm the one who had it towed.
你
You?
没想到姐这招吧
Didn't see that one coming, did ya?
是吗
Oh, yeah?
那你想得到姐这招吗
Well, you're not gonna see this coming.
天啊  你没事吧
Oh, my God, are you okay?!
你包里装了什么鬼东西啊
What the hell do you have in there?!
只有钱包  钥匙和一个装满硬币的咖啡罐
Just my wallet, keys and a coffee can full of change
我正准备到银行存呢
I've been meaning to take to the bank.
别动  我去拿点冰块
Don't move. I'll get some ice.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
离我远点  不然我发誓
Get away from me or I swear to God
我会把你"那块"撕烂
I will rip out what's left of your pubes!
-给  -谢谢
- Here. - Thanks. Ah!
艾米  你不觉得这事有点失控吗
Amy, you think maybe this has gotten a little out of hand?
老天  你才觉得吗
Gee, you think?!
确实
I do.
佩妮  我和伯纳黛特很抱歉
Penny, Bernadette and I are sorry.
打她的是你  我做啥了
You hit her! What did I do?
你拖走了我的车
You had my car towed.
谁叫你在霍华德的车位停车的
You were parked in Howard's spot!
我是停在谢尔顿的车位上的
I was parked in Sheldon's spot!
谢尔顿根本就没有车位
Sheldon doesn't have a spot!
姑娘们  我觉得我得去趟急救室
Guys, I think I need to go to the emergency room.
-好  我们走  -我来开车
- Okay, let's go. - I'll drive.
你可以看看拖吊车把我的车刮成什么样了
You can see where the tow truck scratched my car.
拖吊车根本没刮到你的车
The tow truck didn't scratch your car.
-你怎么知道  -因为是老娘亲自拖的
- How do you know? - 'Cause I did it!
早啊  史蒂文斯教授
Morning, Professor Stevens.
别盯着白板看
Don't look at that whiteboard.
那是我的数学公式  不关你的事
That's my math, not your math.
继续走你的路  事儿妈
Keep walking, nosey.
你又搞什么鬼呢
What the hell are you doing?
你说我没有使用我的车位  所以
You said I'm not using my space, so...
我正在使用
I'm using it.
你得闪边了
Okay, you need to move now.
才不
No, I don't.
你总不可能一直占着那里吧
You can't stay there forever.
事实上  我腿上绑的塑"尿"袋说是可能的
Actually, I have a plastic baggy strapped to my leg that says I can.
放弃吧  沃罗威茨
Give up, Wolowitz.
你的对手比你足智多谋  你赢不了的
You've chosen to tangle with a superior intellect you can't defeat.
你没有任何招能...
There is nothing you could possibly do to...
那玩意没用的  谢尔顿
Those aren't gonna help you, Sheldon!
作用可大了
Oh, yes, they are!
不  你说啥来着
I mean, what?!
我警告你  谢尔顿
I'm warning you, Sheldon!
你吓唬谁啊
Your threats are empty!
我是赶不走的
Nothing can move me!
快住手
Stop that!
滚出我的车位
Get out of my spot!
够了
That's it.
我要叫保安了
I am calling campus security!
你准备好被骂得狗血淋头吧
You prepare for the scolding of your life!
你们两个蠢货干嘛呢
What are you idiots doing?!
他要谋杀我  莱纳德
He's trying to kill me, Leonard!
电玩游戏与摇滚乐
Video games and rock music
令他变得对暴力麻木不仁
have desensitized him to violence!
拜托你好好劝几句
Would you please talk some sense
你的疯子室友行吗
into your lunatic roommate?
你俩都像疯子似的
You're both acting like lunatics.
-一个停车位而已  -不仅仅是停车位
- It's just a parking spot. - It's not just a parking spot!
他无法接受现在
He can't handle the fact that
我比他还大咖的事实
I'm a bigger deal than he is now.
真是荒谬
Oh, preposterous!
我全权负责
I have been solely responsible
这间大学的六回圈量子引力计算
for this university's six-loop quantum gravity calculations;
我改变了世人
I have changed the way we think
对玻色-爱因斯坦凝聚体的想法
about Bose-Einstein condensates,
而且是我让咱学校的食堂贩卖机
and I am also the one who got Nutter Butters
出售花生酱三明治饼
in the cafeteria vending machine.
也许你不知道这些
Maybe you missed that news while you were
因为当时你像个傻子一样在太空里瞎飘
floating around like a goof in outer space.
恕我失陪  我要工作了
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have work to do.
你相信他说的是人话吗
Can you believe this guy?
我不相信你居然想碾死他
What I don't believe is that you tried to run him over.
别装得好像你没想过这么做一样
Oh, like you've never thought of doing that.
别因为我实现梦想而恨我
Don't hate me just because I lived the dream.
嘿  真是辆好车哦
Hey. Sweet ride!
你在车里干什么
What are you doing in there?!
闯入你的新车玩玩啊
Just breaking in your new car.
别这样  快住手
Stop that! You stop that!
知道常言怎么说吗
You know what they say?
君子报仇  裸着才完
Revenge is a dish best served nude.
有时间吗
Hey, got a minute?
当然  请进
Oh, of course, come in.
这是枚货真价实的中国飞镖
This is an authentic Chinese throwing star,
我得警告你
and I must warn you,
我在电影里见过很多人扔这个
I have seen many people throw them in movies.
冷静
Calm down.
霍华德有话跟你说
Howard has something he wants to say to you.
好了
All right.
谢尔顿  这场停车位之战开始后
Sheldon, when this whole thing with the parking space started,
我不知道你是个如此疯狂的混...
I had no idea just how much of a crazy bastard...
霍华德
Howard...
跟着练习时的剧本走
that's not how we practiced it.
我不知道那个停车位对你来说这么重要
I had no idea how much that spot meant to you.
总之  我打了电话给塞伯特校长
Anyway, I called President Siebert
我跟他说争停车位不值得
and told him it's not worth fighting over the spot,
你留着吧  我就停在
so you keep it, and I'll park
街对面的停车场好了
in the structure across the street.
霍华德  谢谢你
Well, Howard, thank you.
你这样做很有风度
It's quite a gesture on your part.
你证明了你是豁然大度的汉子
You've shown yourself to be the bigger man.
谢谢
Thank you.
我完全不能接受这结果
Which I find totally unacceptable.
我一定得比人大度才行
I must be the bigger man.
因此  你可以用我的停车位直到
Therefore, you may use my spot until such time
我学会开车  或是有了蝙蝠车
as I learn to drive or get a Batmobile.
好的
Wow, okay.
谢谢
Well, thanks.
我不知道说什么好了
I don't know what to say.
没什么好说的
There is nothing to say.
除了"你才是大度真汉子"
Except I'm the bigger man.
我没开玩笑  快说
I'm not kidding. Say it.
说吧
Just say it.
你才是大度真汉子  谢尔顿
You're the bigger man, Sheldon.
少来了
Oh, stop.
我相信这个是你的
And I believe this is yours.
告诉你  如果戴着这个进银行
FYI, if you wear that into a bank,
保安会把你摁倒在地
they will tackle you to the ground.
大家来干一杯吧
I'd like to propose a toast--
敬恩怨一笔勾销
to burying the hatchet.
To burying the hatchet.
我有点开心发生这样的事
You know, I'm kind of glad this happened.
我也是
Me, too.
虽说有些怪异  但我感觉让我们更亲近了
In some weird way, I kind of feel like it brought us closer.
皆大欢喜  好耶
Yeah, everybody's happy. Great!
有什么可以效劳的
Can I help you?
是的  根据我从商户点评网上
Yes. According to information
了解到的信息
I gleaned from Yelp,
网友圣塔拉苏茜37
you had great success when a santeriasuzy37
拿来沾有鸡血的皮裤
brought you a pair of leather slacks
而你成功处理了
stained with chicken blood.
我可能有着同样棘手的问题
I believe I may have a similar problem.
这张座垫  经历了复仇裸蹭
This cushion experienced a nude revenge wiggle.
什么
A what?
一个裸男坐在了上面
A naked man sat on it.
我担心的问题是
Now, here's my concern:
他的饮食成分富含脂肪过多的肉食
His diet is rich in fatty deli meats.
你这里有哪些脂质残留的检验测试呢
What test do you have to detect lipid residue?
什么脂质
Lipid what?
脂质残留
Lipid residue.
亲屁签名
An anal autograph.
叫结肠名片也行
A colon calling card, if you will.
周二拿行吗
Tuesday okay?
慢慢来  好好弄
Don't rush it.
玷污程度可能已经达到
We may be dealing with befoulment
分子级别了
on a molecular level.
我给你开取货单
Let me write you a ticket.
那是你儿子吗
Is that your son?
看起来那个笔记本已经用了一段时日了
Looks like that laptop's seen better days.
有兴趣的话  我在出售这个
If you're interested, I'm selling this.
只用了两年
It's only two years old,
16G内存
16 gigabytes of RAM,
英特尔芯片  I7处理器
Intel core, i7 processor,
而且我可以担保
and I can personally guarantee
它放在一名男性宇航员性器官上的时间
it has spent less than 20 minutes resting on
少于20分钟
an astronaut's penis.